<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on EdTech Reviews</title>
    <link>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on EdTech Reviews</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:56:14 -0230</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:56:14 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>This is the introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Padlet</title>
      <link>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/padlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:55:25 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/padlet/</guid>
      <description>Padlet Overview Padlet is collaboration tool for collecting articles, videos, music, text and photos. It is like an online bulletin board and can be used for gathering related material for an idea or theme. The materials are organized in column that can be used to further break down the topic. User can add, view and modify the padlet in real time.
Homepage: padlet.com Platform: MacOS or Online (accessed via browser)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackMD</title>
      <link>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/hackmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:54:31 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/hackmd/</guid>
      <description>HackMD Overview HackMD is a collaborative online editor for Markdown files. Markdown is a simplified markup language that allow you to quickly format your documents while you write. HackMD provides an editor tailored for Markdown that provides a live rendering of the formatting as you type. The site also allows for multiple users to work on the document simultaneously.
Website Link: hackmd.io Platform: Online (There is also a standalone application supported on Windows, MacOS and Linux)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 18:53:05 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edtech.briankidney.ca/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>Jupyter Notebooks Overview Jupyter Notebook is an open-source web application that can be used to produce and share documents that include a mixture of text, live code examples, equations, and visualization. These can be used in many fields as live teaching documents that embed examples the students can run themselves or modify and run to expand their understanding of the topic. They are commonly used in courses to illustrate data science, scientific simulation or to teach software development itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
